<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<front>
<pb n="i" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
<titlePage>
<docTitle>
<titlePart type="main"><b>ANALYTICAL INDEX TO THE LAWS OF TEXAS, 1823 = 1905.</b></titlePart>
</docTitle>
<byline>(BOTH DATES INCLUSIVE).</byline>
<byline>BY <docAuthor>CADWELL WALTON RAINES</docAuthor>,</byline>
<byline>F<smcap>ELLOW</smcap> T<smcap>HE</smcap> T<smcap>EXAS</smcap> S<smcap>TATE</smcap> H<smcap>ISTORICAL</smcap> A<smcap>SSOCIATION</smcap>; M<smcap>EMBER</smcap> T<smcap>HE</smcap> A<smcap>MERICAN</smcap> H<smcap>ISTORICAL</smcap> A<smcap>SSOCIATION</smcap>; C<smcap>OMPILER</smcap> B<smcap>IBLIOGRAPHY OF</smcap> T<smcap>EXAS</smcap>; Y<smcap>EAR</smcap> B<smcap>OOKS FOR</smcap> T<smcap>EXAS</smcap>, 1901-1903; A<smcap>UTHOR OF</smcap> L<smcap>IFE OF</smcap> S<smcap>ANTA</smcap> A<smcap>NNA</smcap>; E<smcap>DITOR OF</smcap> S<smcap>TATE</smcap> P<smcap>APERS AND</smcap> S<smcap>PEECHES OF</smcap> J<smcap>AMES</smcap> S<smcap>TEPHEN</smcap> H<smcap>OGG</smcap>, E<smcap>X</smcap>-G<smcap>OVERNOR OF</smcap> T<smcap>EXAS</smcap>; E<smcap>DITOR OF</smcap> S<smcap>IX</smcap> D<smcap>ECADES IN</smcap> T<smcap>EXAS</smcap>, <smcap>OR</smcap> M<smcap>EMOIRS OF</smcap> F<smcap>RANCIS</smcap> R<smcap>ICHARD</smcap> L<smcap>UBBOCK</smcap>, E<smcap>X</smcap>-G<smcap>OVERNOR OF</smcap> T<smcap>EXAS</smcap>.</byline>
<byline>F<smcap>RED</smcap> B. R<smcap>OTHMAN</smcap> &#38; C<smcap>O</smcap>. <i>Littleton, Colorado 80127</i> 1987</byline>
</titlePage>
<pb n="ii" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ii" />
<p><b>Library of Congress Cataloging-in-Publication Data</b></p>
<p>Raines, Cadwell Walton, 1839-1906.</p>
<p>Analytical index to the laws of Texas, 1823-1905, both dates inclusive.</p>
<p>Reprint. Originally published: Austin, Tex. :</p>
<p>Von Boeckmann-Jones, 1906.</p>
<p>1. Law--Texas--Indexes. I. Title.</p>
<p>KFT1240.R35 1987 349.764&#8217;016 87-20514</p>
<p>ISBN 0-8377-2534-8 (alk. paper) 347.640016</p>
<figure xml:id="fig1">
<graphic url="images/ii_001.jpg"/>
</figure>
<p>The paper used in this publication meets the minimum requirements of American National Standard for Information Sciences&#8212;Permanence of Paper for Printed Library Materials, ANSI Z39.48-1984.</p>
<pb n="iii" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iii" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">A<smcap>NALYTICAL</smcap> I<smcap>NDEX</smcap> <lb/>TO THE <lb/>L<smcap>AWS OF</smcap> T<smcap>EXAS</smcap>, <lb/>1823 = 1905.</head>
<byline>(BOTH DATES INCLUSIVE).</byline>
<byline>BY C<smcap>ADWELL</smcap> W<smcap>ALTON</smcap> R<smcap>AINES</smcap>.</byline>
<byline>F<smcap>ELLOW</smcap> T<smcap>HE</smcap> T<smcap>EXAS</smcap> S<smcap>TATE</smcap> H<smcap>ISTORICAL</smcap> A<smcap>SSOCIATION</smcap>; M<smcap>EMBER</smcap> T<smcap>HE</smcap> A<smcap>MERICAN</smcap> H<smcap>ISTORICAL</smcap> A<smcap>SSOCIATION</smcap>; C<smcap>OMPILER</smcap> B<smcap>IBLIOGRAPHY OF</smcap> T<smcap>EXAS</smcap>; Y<smcap>EAR</smcap> B<smcap>OOKS FOR</smcap> T<smcap>EXAS</smcap>. 1901-1903; A<smcap>UTHOR OF</smcap> L<smcap>IFE OF</smcap> S<smcap>ANTA</smcap> A<smcap>NNA</smcap>; E<smcap>DITOR OF</smcap> S<smcap>TATE</smcap> P<smcap>APERS AND</smcap> S<smcap>PEECHES OF</smcap> J<smcap>AMES</smcap> S<smcap>TEPHEN</smcap> H<smcap>OGG</smcap>, E<smcap>X</smcap>-G<smcap>OVERNOR OF</smcap> T<smcap>EXAS</smcap>; E<smcap>DITOR OF</smcap> S<smcap>IX</smcap> D<smcap>ECADES IN</smcap> T<smcap>EXAS</smcap>, <smcap>OR</smcap> M<smcap>EMOIRS OF</smcap> F<smcap>RANCIS</smcap> R<smcap>ICHARD</smcap> L<smcap>UBBOCK</smcap>, E<smcap>X</smcap>-G<smcap>OVERNOR OF</smcap> T<smcap>EXAS</smcap>.</byline>
<byline>1906: V<smcap>ON</smcap> B<smcap>OECKMANN</smcap>-J<smcap>ONES</smcap> C<smcap>OMPANY</smcap>, P<smcap>RINTERS</smcap>, A<smcap>USTIN</smcap>, T<smcap>EXAS</smcap>.</byline>
<pb n="iv" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iv" />
<byline>COPY RIGHTED 1906 BY C. W. RAINES.</byline>
<pb n="v" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="v" />
<byline>TO THE TEXAS BAR ASSOCIATION THIS VOLUME IS DEDICATED BY THE AUTHOR</byline>
<byline>WITH THE HOPE THAT IT MAY PROVE HELPFUL TO ALL ITS MEMBERS AND THE PROFESSION AT LARGE AS WELL.</byline>
<byline>Austin, June 2, 1906.</byline>
<byline>C. W. RAINES.</byline>
<pb n="vi" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vi" />
<pb n="vii" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vii" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">PREFACE.</head>
<p>I have been engaged at available times for several years in preparing an Index to the Laws of Texas, and this volume is the result. Within the past twelve months, however, the whole work has been overhauled, the classification modified, the sentences in a great measure recast and the system of cross-indexing more fully elaborated. The last substantial improvement in the make-up of the book on my original plan is the printing it in double columns and smaller type, thus reducing considerably the number of pages, but bringing out all the work as originally contemplated. This Index extends from 1823 to the regular session of the Twenty-ninth Legislature inclusive, and em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />braces in its scope the legislation of all intermediate governments; that is, the legislation of Coahuila and Texas; that of the Provisional Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment and Republic of Texas and of the State of Texas under its several Constitutions.</p>
<p>Not only the bench and bar but the heads of the State Departments and all State Institutions, including the University, will find, I trust, this Index very helpful in finding the laws wanted. This is no less true for all those concerned in banks and banking, insurance, railroads and, in fact, corporations generally.</p>
<p>The strong points claimed for this Index are: Its classification; its analytical features; its clearness of statement; its numerous allusions to historic personages and events gleaned from the laws and documents at large; its elaborate system of cross-indexing, and finally its not being restricted to the caption of the laws.</p>
<p>In conclusion, much is due to the care and ability of Mr. E. H. Loughery in the completion of the work and in running it through the press, a large part of the constructive work devolving on him, owing to my failing health.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Austin, Texas, <date>June 20, 1906</date>.</dateline>
<signed>C. W. R<smcap>AINES</smcap>.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="viii" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="viii" />
<pb n="ix" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ix" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">EXPLANATION.</head>
<p>The Analytical Index covers the ten volume reprint of laws, etc., pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished some years since, and acts of the Twenty-sixth, Twenty-seventh, Twenty-eighth and Twenty-ninth Legislatures. Wherever Volume 11 is referred to is meant acts of the Twenty-sixth and Twenty-seventh Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islatures. Wherever Volume 12 is referred to is meant acts of the Twenty-eighth and Twenty-ninth Legislatures. For convenience, in in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dexing, I had the acts of those Legislatures bound in two volumes, 11 and 12, and the pages contained in them, numbered on the same plan as those in the ten-volume collection; with the idea, also, of reprinting and supplying them to the profession in that form, should there be a demand for them. Persons having the acts of the Twenty-sixth to Twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ninth Legislatures, inclusive, can use them without difficulty in connec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion with the Analytical Index, the Index supplying information de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sired, and the indexes published with the acts of those bodies enabling inquirers to find it.</p>
<p>The reference figures used in the Analytical Index (for instance, 1<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />1516-1838), indicate volume, page and year of passage of enactment.<lb/> The statements run between parentheses, after subject titles, direct<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the reader to see other titles, are inserted for the purpose of facili<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tating research along kindred lines. As an illustration, under Attach<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments are all acts devoted exclusively to that subject. Practice acts, covering that and other topics, are not listed under it, but under Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict and other Courts to which they refer; and, in addition thereto, are all grouped under Pleading and Practice.</p>
<p>The appropriations contained in general appropriation acts are not listed under the various departments and institutions, but all of said acts are grouped under the single title Support of Government, and only special appropriations made by separate acts placed under them.<lb/> Special acts relating to municipal charters are under Cities, Towns and Villages. Amendments to Revised Statutes, etc., are listed under subjects to which they relate.</p>
<p>A large number of private acts of minor importance, with regard to claims of individuals to lands, etc., are under Abstracts and Relief Acts, some few, unavoidably, finding a place under Land Office, General; Land Office, General, Commissioner of, and Lands.</p>
<p>References to all indexes printed in the volumes are to be found under the title Indexes; and those covering enactments of the Congress of<pb n="x" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="x" />Coahuila and Texas and Congresses of the Republic of Texas, also, under the title Congress; and those covering enactments of the Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture of the State of Texas, under Legislature.</p>
<p>Under Contents are listed in consecutive order the contents of all the volumes, from Volume 1 to 12, inclusive.</p>
<p>As its name imports, the Analytical Index to the Laws of Texas, gives not only single, general citations to acts, etc., but covers full develop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments of subjects, citing all constitutional provisions, proceedings of conventions, provisions of acts, and resolutions, appropriations, etc., re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lating thereto.</p>
<p>The Index does not claim to be perfect but the most painstaking care has been taken to make the errors as few as possible.</p>
</div2>
</div1>
</front>
<body>
<p>Body content follows Chapter_1-560.xml</p>
</body>
</text>
